Ayush Kumar

Ranchi, Jharkhand, India



ayush.singh095@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ayush-ksingh



+91-7991191007, 9472146033



https://ayush94k.github.io/

Summary

Technology Professional having 5+ years of total experience, with 3 years in Project Management and MIS tools. Trained in Gigabit Passive Optical Networks, Project Management Tool based on PMBOK guide, MIS -Management Information Systems, NMS - Network Management Systems, NOC - Network Operations Center, Broadband and Acceptance Tests, Keyhole Markup Language (KML), Primavera, MS office for Project Management and technical training.

Delivered 100% on Project Monitoring tool and MIS for 3 consecutive years.

My Aim is to play my part in developing the everchanging information technology systems present in our society.

Experience



Network Engineer

Bharat Broadband Network Limited

Mar 2019 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

Roles & Responsibility:

- · Responsible for organizing and maintaining Project Management Tools & MIS Portal.
- Monitoring of Network on Network Management Systems.
- Ensuring the use of project management tools by Vendors, auditors, CPSUs and SPSUs.
- Responsible for Preparation of daily/weekly/monthly progress report, scheduling of meeting, Preparation of PPT for meeting, Preparation of meeting agenda, taking meeting notes, Preparation of Minutes of Meeting and circulating it with the concerned officials of state government and central government.
- Coordinating the Site team and monitoring their performance.
- Planning and Monitoring of daily/weekly/monthly progress of 11 district of Jharkhand.
- · Co-ordination with PIA, PMC and Third party auditors for O&M related activities to ensure end to end connectivity and acceptance tests.

Trainee

Power Grid Corporation of India Limited

Mar 2018 - Mar 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Roles & Responsibility:

- Responsible for organizing and maintaining Primavera Project Management Tools.
- Monitoring of Network on Network Management Systems.
- Co-ordination with vendor's team to ensure end to end connectivity.
- Plotting of OFC laying/Network diagram in Google earth based on physical survey.



Site Engineer

RUDRA INFRACITY PRIVATE LIMITED

Jun 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Roles & Responsibility:

- Preparing Progress reports based on the data shared by site team and design team.
- Co-ordination with Site Supervisor, design team and splicing team for O&M related activities to ensure end to end connectivity.

Vocational training

Indian Oil Corporation
Jun 2015 - Jun 2015 (1 month)
Vocational training of two weeks.



Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited

Dec 2013 - Jan 2014 (2 months)

Two week of In Plant Training at Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited Exchange, GMTD office.

Education

Sathyabama University

B.E., Electronics & control Engineering 2012 - 2016

Licenses & Certifications

- The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Google
- **in Cert Prep: Project Management Professional (PMP)**® LinkedIn
- in Networking Foundations: IP Addressing LinkedIn
- Cert Prep: Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (100-105) LinkedIn
- Cisco ICND2 Cert Prep: Infrastructure Services LinkedIn

Skills

Management Information Systems (MIS) • Network Management Systems (NMS) • Network Operations
Center (NOC) • Microsoft Office • Project Management • Network Monitoring Tools • IP Addressing •
Gigabit Passive Optical Networks • Technical Training • Keyhole Markup Language (KML)